Previously on "Better Call Saul..."
Clifford Main hired jimmy.
He had his doubts.
Truth be told, Kim Wexler pushed for this.
You faked evidence.
Mmm, I think you're splitting hairs.
Why would you risk the
best job you've ever had
for some pro-bono case?
I was hoping, maybe,
you could do me a favor.
Anything you need, I'll be there.
You still in touch with your people?
Depends on the type of
work you're looking for.
You tell me what you got.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
Why are you here?
To bear witness.
약간 문제가 생겼어요, 여러분
오래 걸리지 않을거에요
Sorry about the hiccup, folks.
Won't be long.
5분만 주겠어
You got five minutes.
안녕하세요, 여러분
Howdy, folks!
Can someone tell me if Mrs.
Alma May Urbano is on board?
혹시 Alma May Urbano씨 탑승해 계신가요?
Alma May Urbano?
Alma May Urbano씨
거기 계셨군요
안녕하세요
There you are!
Hello, dear.
만나서 반가워요
Very good to meet you.
저는 Jimmy라고 합니다
My name's Jimmy.
제가 샌드파이퍼에서 당신을 만나려 했는데,
I tried to visit
you at Sandpiper,
절 들여보내주지 않더라구요
but they wouldn't allow me to.
그거 아세요?
Hey, you know what?
It doesn't matter.
상관 없어요
I saw your bus broken down.
Here you are! Lucky me!
제가 당신이 탄 버스가 고장난 걸 봤고,
당신은 여기 있구요
좋아요
Urbano씨라 불러드릴까요?
Do you prefer to be called
Mrs. Urbano or Alma May
or just plain Alma?
아니면 Alma May나
그냥 Alma로 불러드릴까요?
제 성은 McGill이지만,
Jimmy라 불러주세요
My last name is McGill,
but you can call me Jimmy.
Hey, everyone.
My name's Jimmy McGill,
여러분!
저는 Jimmy McGill입니다.
I'm an attorney at law. But...
저는 변호사입니다
하지만 신경쓰지 마세요
Don't mind me.
그냥 하던 일 하세요
Just talk amongst yourselves.
Now, Alma May, do you recall responding
to a mailer from my law firm,
그럼, Alma May씨,
New Mexico의 Santa Fe에 있는
제 로펌 Davis & Main에서 보낸
편지에 대해 기억하시나요?
Davis & Main of
Santa Fe, New Mexico?
I... I don't know.
전... 전 잘 모르겠어요
We were looking to help
any Sandpiper residents
저흰 샌드파이퍼 거주자 분들 중
who may have been overcharged
for basic goods and services.
부당하게 과한 금액이 청구된 사람들을
찾고 있어요
기본적인 물품이나 서비스에 대해서요
기억나는 것 같으세요?
Now, does that ring a bell?
오! 아마도요
그거 노란색이었죠?
Oh! Maybe. Was it yellow?
카나리아 노란색이에요
It's canary yellow.
I picked that color myself!
제가 고른 색이죠
Well, ma'am, I'm here to make
sure you get your money back.
부인, 부인께서 당신의 돈을 되찾을 수
있다는 걸 확인시켜드리러 왔어요
What're you talking about?
Who took Alma May's money?
당신 무슨 얘기 하는거요?
누가 Alma May의 돈을 가져갔다구요?
Uh, well,
that's a very good question.
음, 그거 아주 좋은 질문이에요
And thank you for asking,
Mister...
그리고 물어봐주셔서 감사합니다, 성함이...?
Amos... Amos Lydecker요
Amos. Amos Lydecker.
Mr. Lydecker, Jimmy McGill.
Lydecker씨, Jimmy McGill입니다
Now, nobody took
anybody's money, exactly.
아무도 누군가의 돈을 가져가진 않았죠,
정확히는요
Okay? It's not like the
Sandpiper people, you know,
아셨죠?
샌드파이퍼 사람들이 스키마스크를 쓰고,
put on a ski mask and mugged
Alma May here at gunpoint.
Alma May씨를 총구로 겨누어
강도짓 같은 걸 한 건 아니에요
So, I want you to put that mental
image right out of your head.
여러분 마음 속에 바로 떠오른 이미지를
없애드리고 싶네요
See, what we're talking
about here
제가 여기서 얘기하고 있는 건...
is more of a...
It's just a discrepancy.
단지 불일치에요
It's just a little thing.
It's fairly innocent.
이건... 작은 일이에요
이건... 꽤 무죄이구요
But, we need to fix it.
하지만 고쳐야만 합니다
You follow me?
알아듣고 계시죠?
Well, put it this way.
음, 다시 설명 드리죠
Alma May, let's say you're out
on a date with your boyfriend.
Alma May씨, 당신이 당신의 남자친구와
데이트를 한다고 합시다
You do have a boyfriend, right?
남자친구 있으시죠, 그쵸?
아! 없으시다구요?
Ah! You don't? Come on!
Alma May씨가 저한테 숨기고 있네요
Alma May's holding out on me.
조카 있으세요?
Do you have a nephew?
Nephew? Oh, yes. Steve.
조카요?
네... Steve요
Okay, Steve,
is he a good guy?
네, Steve군요
- 착한 녀석인가요?
- 네, 아주 착한 애에요
Yes, very good.
Okay. So let's say you and
Steve go out to dinner at,
좋아요
당신과 Steve가 저녁을 먹으러 갔다고 해봅시다
음... Birdie's에요
well, Birdie's.
That's where you're
all headed today, right?
그 곳이 다들 오늘 가시는 곳이죠?
All right.
좋아요
So, both of you
have a great meal.
그래서, 두 분 모두 좋은 식사를 했어요
Chicken fried steak and green
beans, and it's all perfect.
치킨 스테이크와 그린빈이었고,
모두 완벽했어요
Here comes the check...
계산서가 나왔네요
"Hey, wait a dog-gone, 24 bucks for
a side of buttermilk biscuits?"
"이런 망할놈의..."
곁들여 먹은 버터밀크 비스킷이 24불이라고?
- That doesn't sound right now, does it?
- No.
"이거 말이 안되잖아, 말이 돼 이게?"
No, it does not. It sounds like
something got added up wrong.
아뇨, 말이 안되죠.
뭔가 잘못 계산된 것 같아요
Well naturally, you send your nephew,
Steve, to talk to the manager.
물론, 조카 Steve를 보내서
매니저와 얘기하도록 하겠죠
And naturally, the manager
corrects the mistake.
그리고 물론, 매니저는 실수를 수정하겠죠
And what's more,
he gives you a coupon
그리고 게다가, 매니저가 당신에게 쿠폰을 주네요
for a free meal next time you come in.
How about that!
다음에 왔을 때 무료로 한 번 먹을 수 있게요
이건 어떤가요?
좋아요
Well, that same kind of thing is
what happened at Sandpiper Crossing.
음, 이것과 같은 일이
샌드파이퍼 크로싱에서 일어났어요
And nothing makes me sadder
그리고 절 가장 슬프게 하는 건요
than to see people
of the Greatest Generation,
가장 위대한 세대의 사람들이,
people like my
own Nana and Bobo,
제가 사랑하는 할머니, 할아버지와 같은 분들이
거대한 회사에게 과잉청구되는 걸 보는 게
제일 슬프답니다
getting overcharged
by some great big company.
Even if it was an accident.
그게 사고였다고 하더라도 말이죠
Now, I know that
the good people
샌드파이퍼에도 좋은 사람이 있는 걸 알아요
at Sandpiper want
to make this right.
늦든 빠르든 이 일을 바로 잡고 싶어하는 사람을요
근데 그거 아세요?
Sooner or later.
But you know what?
Well, sometimes,
가끔씩은, 이렇게 하는 게 더 쉬워요
it's just easier
if you get your nephew, Steve,
to go take care of it for you.
조카 Steve를 보내 당신의 일을
처리하게 한다면요
And that's how I
want you to think of me.
그리고 당신이 저를 그렇게 봐주셨으면 해요
Georgiana. Hey there, Georgie Girl.
Thank you.
Georgiana.
감사합니다
Oh! It's all there,
everything I need.
여기 다 있네요, 제가 필요한 건 다 있어요
Thank you so much.
Enjoy your lunch.
감사합니다
맛있는 점심 되세요
Alma May. You did it. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Alma May, 해내셨어요
정말 감사합니다
감사합니다
감사합니다, Henry
Thank you, Henry.
All right. Hey, Sue...
좋아요
Hey, Sue. 좋아요
Okay.
아름다운 글씨체네요
Beautiful penmanship!
A lost art...
잃어버린 예술작품이군요
Better Call Saul
Season 2 Episode 3
번역포럼 콩냥 제작
오역, 의역 양해 부탁드립니다
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
Schweikart & Cokely는 공격적인
전략으로 밀고 나가고 있어요
Schweikart and Cokely are
pursuing an aggressive strategy,
하지만 제가 관련있는 판례를 살펴보았는데요,
but looking at
the relevant case law,
제 생각에 이번 치안 판사가
그들에게 그리 호락호락하지 않을 것 같아요
※ 치안 판사: 약식 재판의 권한을 가지는 재판관
I don't think it's going to play
with this magistrate judge.
그녀가 내린 판결을
12개는 넘게 읽어보았어요
I've read over a dozen of
her rulings, all of which
이런 것과 비슷한 사건에서
전부 원고의 편을 들었어요
have sided with the plaintiff
on cases like this.
오늘자 자료에 그 영향에 대한
메모를 첨부했어요
I've included a memo to that
effect in today's materials,
쉬는 시간에 정독하실 수 있을거에요
which you can
peruse at your leisure.
고마워요, Erin
Thanks, Erin. How about we
move on to client outreach?
고객 응대에 대한 얘기로 넘어갑시다
Jimmy?
잘 따라오고 있는건가?
어...
You still with us?
자랑할 시간을 절약해주겠어요
Uh...
I'm going to save you
from having to brag.
지난 3주 동안 200명이 넘는
샌드파이퍼 고객들이
Over 200 new Sandpiper clients
signed over the past three weeks.
새로 사인을 했어요
잘 했어요, Jimmy
고마워요
고마워요, Cliff
Well done, Jimmy.
Thank you.
지금 당장은,
Thanks, Cliff.
우린 남서부 쪽을 진행 중이에요
Uh, right now,
we're in the process
of mapping out
the entire Southwest,
가장 큰 샌드파이퍼 시설을
최우선적으로 목표해서요
targeting the largest
Sandpiper facilities first.
Phoenix, Colorado Springs,
Fort Worth, Provo...
Fort Worth, Provo.
이건 그저 출발일 뿐입니다
That's just for starters.
이상적으로, 제 목표는... 이번 달 말까지
200명을 추가로 계약하려 합니다
Ideally, my goal, another 200
by the end of the month.
이 많은 사람들이 있다면,
저흰 각 지역마다
With this many folks, we have an
excellent shot at a solid batch
견고하게 엮인 여러 명의 원고들과 함께
좋은 시도를 할 수 있을거에요
of plaintiffs for the classes
in each district.
훌륭해요
다음 번 보고를 기다리겠습니다
Excellent. Look forward
to the next report.
난감해지고 있는...
조정 시도에 대해 얘기해봅시다
On to a stickier wicket,
coordinating actions.
죄송합니다만
다음 주제로 넘어가기 전에,
Um, sorry.
Before we move on.
I'd like to go back to client
outreach, just for a moment.
잠시 고객 응대에 대해 얘기하고 싶은데요
여기 적힌 숫자들을 보면,
Looking over
these numbers, here.
정말, 정말 놀라운 결과에요, Jimmy
Really astonishing results,
Jimmy. Incredible.
믿을 수가 없네요
최근 다녀온 Amarillo 출장을 살펴보면
Your last trip to Amarillo,
22명의 새로운 고객을 데려왔지요
you came back
with 22 new clients?
- 24명이요
- 24명
Twenty-four.
헷갈렸네요
I'm confused.
음, 얼마나 많은 사람이
Um, how many people
out there actually
실제 우리가 보낸 편지에 응답했나요?
responded to
our direct mailer?
한 명이요
오, 그렇군요
One.
Hmm. Oh, right, yeah.
Alma May Urbano씨
A Mars Alma May Urbano.
그런데 그 한 명의 응답에서
24명의 새로운 고객을 데려왔다구요?
But you got 24 new clients
from this one response?
이건... 놀랍네요
That is...
음, 천만에요
Wow!
Well, you're welcome. I mean,
what, is there a problem?
그러니까, 뭐요? 문제가 있나요?
음, 몇 몇은 아니겠지만...
Well, might not some parties, the
opposing counsel for example,
상대편 변호사가, 예를 들어...
이 차이를 보고
see this differential
and conclude that
이 일에 들어오길 소송 유도했다고
결론내릴 수 있지 않나요?
there may have been some
solicitation involved?
전 소송 유도하지 않았습니다
I did not solicit.
전 그저 당신이 이러한 성공에 대해
어떻게 해명할지 걱정돼서 그러는 겁니다
I'm just wondering how you
account for your success.
왜냐하면 분명히 Schweikart & Cokely가
Because it will definitely raise
eyebrows over at Schweikart and Cokely.
이것에 대해 비난할 것이기 때문입니다
죄송합니다만, 그럴거에요
특히 노인이 연관된 사건에서
I'm sorry, but it will.
Particularly in a case
involving seniors
사실상 변호사 협회가 소송 유도에 대한
for whom
the ethical guidelines
on solicitation were virtually
created by the ABA.
윤리적 가이드라인을 만들었으니 말이에요
Chuck, 내가 확신하는데...
Chuck, I'm sure that...
Jimmy, 이 건을 정리할 수 있다면,
Jimmy, if you could clear this
up that would be helpful.
매우 도움이 될텐데 말이지
저는 고객과 상의하기 위해 Amarillo로 갔어요
I went to Amarillo to
confer with the client
그리고 저희는 굳건하고, 선의의 뜻을
갖고 있다는 걸 확인시켜 드렸죠
and to make sure that we had
a solid good-faith basis
우리의 사건에서나, 전반적으로요
for our case there.
Overall.
그리고 다들 알고 계시고 있듯이,
As many of you are aware,
저는 제 몫보다 많은 수의 고객을 방문했습니다
I've visited more than
my share of retirement homes.
이건 아주 긴밀하게 조직된 공동체에요
These are close-knit communities.
Let me tell you,
제가 말하는데, 말은 정말 빨리 퍼집니다
word gets around real fast.
Phase Two의 Dorothy가
Rascal 스쿠터를 새로 산다면
Dorothy in Phase 2 gets a new Rascal
Scooter, well, it's big news.
이건 큰 사건이죠
그래서 다른 23명의 고객들은,
그들이 당신에게 다가간거죠
So these other 23 residents,
they approached you?
Cliff, 그들은 소문을 들었어요
Cliff, they heard the scuttlebutt
before I crossed state lines.
제가 주 경계선을 넘기도 전에요
그리고 확신하는데
전 그 어떤 문도 두드리지 않았습니다
And I certainly didn't have
to go knockin' on any doors.
그리고 이게 그렇게 놀라운 일인가요?
And is it any surprise
that they wanna
speak with
the guy who was there
돈을 되찾아줄 사람이 그 곳에 있는데
그 사람하고 얘기하길 원하는 게요?
to show them they may have
money coming their way?
제가 말씀드릴 게 있네요
제 마음 속에 있는 말인데
I gotta tell ya, with all that in
mind, I should've done better.
저는 더 잘할 수 있었어요
이해가 되네요
Howard?
Makes sense. Howard?
Chuck?
다음으로 넘어가도 될까요?
We good to move on?
Chuck, 지나가는 말이 아니고
일처리를 꼼꼼하고 정확하게 하는 건
And, Chuck,
not incidentally,
정말 필수적이에요
매우 유용한거죠
it is absolutely vital
that we dot our I's
and cross our T's here.
그러니, 감사합니다
Invaluable. So, thank you.
뛰어남의 대가는 끊임없는 경계심이죠
The price of excellence
is eternal vigilance.
정말로요
Indeed.
조정 시도
Coordination. I believe
that's where we left off.
그게 우리가 마지막에
나눴던 얘기로 기억하네요
That's right. Brian, this is your
thing, so why don't you take this?
맞아요
Brian, 이건 당신의 일이었죠,
이것에 대해 말해보세요
네
Sure.
이번 사건의 규모를 고려했을 때,
Considering the dimensions
of these cases,
다같이 그리고 개인적으로
진행하는 부분에 있어,
taken together
and individually,
일정을 조정하는 사람을
지명하는 게 좋아보입니다
it makes sense to designate
someone to handle the scheduling.
제가 제안하고자 하는 것은 D&M에서
What I'm proposing is that we
create a small team at D&M
개인 행동을 조정하는데 헌신할 수 있는
작은 팀을 만드는 것입니다
dedicated specifically
to coordinating
all elements of the
individual actions.
- We'll loop in HHM on anything...
- 어, Brian, 죄송합니다
We'll loop in HHM
when anything...
Brian. I'm sorry.
Excuse me for interrupting.
방해해서 죄송합니다
어, 저는 단지 제가 Chuck의 논점을
이해했다고 말하고 싶네요
I just want to say that
I take Chuck's point.
정말로요
I do.
제 말은, 이건 시저의 아내와 같은 얘기라는 거에요
※ "시저의 아내까지도 단순한 소문을 두려워할 만큼
깨끗해야 한다" 라는 말이 있음
I mean, this is like a
"wife of Caesar" type thing.
There can't even be a hint of
solicitation, so I'm gonna pull back.
소송 유도의 실마리가 될 수도 없지만요
그러니 저는 철수하겠습니다
좋아요, 샌드파이퍼 시설에서의
No more meet-and-greets
at Sandpiper facilities.
미팅은 이제 없을겁니다
제가 진행할 다른 방법을 찾아보겠습니다
I'll find another way
to proceed.
음, Jimmy, 그게 당신이 할 일이에요
Well, Jimmy,
we'll leave that up to you.
고객 응대가 당신의 업무죠
You know, client outreach
is your department.
어, 어디까지 했죠?
Uh, where was I?
Okay, right.
아, 여기군요
만약 우리가 이 곳, 뉴 멕시코에
좀 더 조직화된 중심 부서가 있다면
If we have a more
consolidated nerve center
here in New Mexico,
where the...
Kim, 내가 어디서
Neiderman 녹취록을 얻을 수 있을까?
Hey, Kim, where can I get a copy
of that Neiderman deposition?
내가 여분의 녹취록이 있어, Jimmy
I've got an extra Neiderman, Jimmy.
You can have one of mine.
내 것 중 하나 가져가
오, 고마워, Erin
Oh, wow, thanks, Erin.
걱정마
No worries.
이런. 내가 어디에 놨지?
Shoot.
Where did I put that?
고마워, 그거...
Thanks that's...
이런, Chuck이 여기있는 게 믿겨져?
Man, can you believe
Chuck in there?
젠장. 소송 유도?
I mean, Jesus.
Solicitation?
너한테만 말하자면, 우리가 이 사건을 만들 때,
Let me tell you, when we
were building this case,
나는 80살 먹은 마트 직원을 쫓아다녔어
I was chasing down
eighty-year-old mall walkers.
그게 소송 유도라고
That was solicitation!
But did he say "boo"?
그런데도 그가 야유를 보내?
그가 한 건 헛소리라구
Bullshit, he did!
텍사스에서 무슨 일이 있었어?
What happened in Texas?
아무것도
Nothing. I did my job.
난 내 일을 했어
You didn't do a song and dance in
the day room for the old-timers?
노인들을 위해 휴게실에서
노래 부르고 춤 추지 않았다고?
아니, 아니
No! No.
휴게실이 아니었어
Not in the day room.
Jimmy, you know solicitation can
get you disbarred. This matters.
Jimmy, 소송 유도하는 게 변호사 자격을
박탈당할 수도 있다는 걸 알잖아
이건 문제가 되는 일이야
내가 생각하는 문제가 되는 일은...
Well, here's what
I think matters,
24명의 노인들이 이제 대표자가 생겼어
twenty-four senior citizens
now have representation.
내가 가기 전엔,
Before I went they didn't even
know they were getting ripped off.
그 사람들은 그들이 빼앗기는 줄도 몰랐어
Now they have us in their corner.
How is that not a win?
이제 우리가 그들의 편에 있는거야
이게 어떻게 승리한 게 아니야?
아까 거기서 다른 방법을 찾아본다고 했지
You said in there
you'd find another way.
진심이야?
Did you mean it?
그래, 당연하지
나는...
Sure. Absolutely.
봐봐, 나는...
Look, I...
난 너가 여기서 정말 위험한 게
무엇인지 이해하면 좋겠어
I need you to understand
something very critical here.
말해봐
Shoot.
나는 너가 이 일을 얻게 하기 위해
내 목숨도 내걸었어
I put myself on
the line to get you this job.
어, 알겠어
Okay.
난 이번 일은 내가 노인들에게
인기가 많아서라고 생각해
I thought it was because I'm
sensational with old people.
그래, 그리고 누가 그걸 말해줬는데?
Yeah, and who do you
think told them that?
그래서, 뭐... 날 돕는 시늉만 하는거야?
So what
you threw me a bone?
아냐... 멍청아
No. Asshole.
내가 널 믿는 걸 알잖아
You know
I believe in you.
그런데 내 믿음을 그들에게 설득했고
But then I made my
beliefs known to them.
Now everything you do reflects back on me.
With Howard.
그리고 너가 하는 모든 일은
나와 Howard에게 영향이 오게 돼
왜냐하면 결국엔, 나도 그에게
Because ultimately,
I talked him into
위험을 감수하도록 설득하게 될거니까
going out on
a limb for you, too.
알아들었어?
Do you understand? It's, it's my word.
It's my judgment.
이건... 이건... 이건 나에 대한 신뢰성이야
이건 내 판단력이라고
알았어
Yeah.
너가 이 일을 할 수 있다는 걸
우리 둘 다 알잖아
You and I both know
you can do this job.
But please,
you just have to do it right.
하지만 제발, 올바르게 해
음... 건전지를 제대로 된 방향으로
넣었는 지 확인해야 한단다
Well...
You wanna make sure you put in
the batteries the right way.
아니면 동작하지 않는단다
Or it won't work.
그리고 닫으면 되지
Then you close him up.
그리고...
And...
내 생각엔 잘 된 것 같구나, 아가씨
I think...
I think you're good
to go, young lady.
한 번 인형의 발을 눌러보지 않으련?
Why don't you give
his foot a squeeze?
재밌어요!
He's funny!
오, 얘야
Oh, darling...
너의 이름은... Snuggles야
I think I'll name you...
Mr. Snuggles.
배고프니?
Are you hungry?
매쉬 포테이토를 조금 가져다 줄 수 있어
I'm gonna get you
some mashed potatoes.
이거로 다음 달까지 버틸 수 있을거야
That should get you
through to next month.
아버님, 고마워요
Mike, thank you.
그런데 정말 이런 거 해주지 않으셔도...
But you shouldn't
feel that you need to...
너무 늦었다
Too late.
무슨 일 있니?
Something up?
무슨 일 있는 것 같아 보이는데
Feels like something's up.
No. It's...
I didn't get much sleep.
아니에요, 이건...
잠을 푹 자지 못했어요
My head's...
- 머리가...
- 미안하구나
I'm sorry.
이게 내 일이 아니라고 한다면,
나는 신경쓰지 않겠다
You tell me it's none of
my business, I'll drop it.
아버님이 걱정하지 않으면 좋겠어요
I don't want you to worry.
걱정하는 거 아니란다
Not the worrying kind.
지난 두 밤 동안, 총소리를 들었어요
Last two nights,
I heard gunshots.
첫 날 밤엔 한 두 블럭 거리였고
First night, they were maybe a
block or two over. Woke me up.
그게 절 깨웠어요
처음에 든 생각은 폭죽인가 했어요
My first thought
was firecrackers,
그게 그 시간에 했던 생각이에요
I mean, that's what I
assumed at the time.
그런데 그리고 지난 밤엔...
실수가 없었어요
But then last night...
There's no mistaking it. There was
three of them. They were quick.
셋이 있었어요
그들은 빨랐고... 탕, 탕, 탕... 가까워졌어요
Pop, pop, pop Closer.
그건 마치...
It was like they
were right outside the house.
집 바로 밖에 있는 것 같았어요
경찰을 불렀니?
You call the cops?
네
Yeah.
Took 'em over
an hour to get here,
여기까지 오는데 한 시간 넘게 걸렸는데
then they looked around
for a whole two minutes.
그러고는 2분만에 주변을 둘러보더라구요
But by then, of course,
there was nothing to see.
하지만 그 땐 이미,
당연히도, 아무것도 없었죠
오늘 밤엔 내가 여기에 있으마
I'm staying here tonight.
아녜요, 아버님
아니에요
No, Mike.
No, that's not necessary.
그럴 필요 없어요
It is not a problem.
I'll take the couch.
아니다, 이건 문제될 게 없단다
내가 소파에서 자마
Mike, you asked,
so I answered.
아버님, 아버님이 물었고, 그래서...
제가 대답했잖아요
제가 말한 걸 죄송하게 만들지 마세요
Please, don't make me sorry
I told you.
Kaylee, come, hmm?
Kaylee, 와볼래?
Get your supper.
저녁 먹자
Colorado Springs는 어때?
What about Colorado Springs?
음...
283명의 거주자가 있고,
283개의 우편을 보냈습니다
Um...
Two hundred and eighty-three
residents, and...
We sent out 283 mailers.
좋아, 그리고 답변은 얼마나 많이 받았나?
Yeah, and how many
response cards came back?
0이요
0?
Zero.
Zero?
빌어먹을
Son of a bitch.
Dana, Toni, 좋은 하루 보내세요
Dana, Toni.
Have a good one.
당신두요, Main씨
You too, Mr. Main.
Cliff씨, 잠깐 시간 되시나요?
Cliff, uh,
can I have a second?
무슨 일인가요?
어, 샌드파이퍼에 우편 보내는 것 말인데요
What's up?
Uh, it's those
Sandpiper mailers.
우린 분명 12%에서 15%의
응답을 받아야 할텐데,
We should be getting
responses of like 12 to 15%.
한 개나 두 개 정도만 받고 있어요
But we're
getting ones and twos.
Colorado Springs에선, 하나도 못 받았구요
In Colorado Springs, zero.
어떻게 그렇게 됐죠?
Wow!
How can that be?
제 생각엔 직원 같아요
I'm thinking it's the staff.
그들이 편지를 버리는거죠
They're tossing the mailers before
they can reach the residents.
편지가 거주자한테 가기도 전에요
아마 샌드파이퍼 경영 부서에
의해 지시되었을거에요
Maybe they got told to do it
by the Sandpiper front office.
이건 아주 지옥같은 소송이
걸릴 수 있는 문제죠
Which would be
actionable as hell.
만약 우리가 그걸 증명한다면
아주 큰 "만약"이지
If we could prove it.
그리고 그렇게 하기 위해선
내가 감당할 수 있는 인력을 넘어서지요
Big "if."
And to do so would take more
manpower than I can spare.
지금으로선, 고객들의 수를
올리는 데에 집중합시다
For now, let's just stick with
getting those client numbers up.
당신이 다른 좋은 방법을 생각해낼 수 있을거에요
Guess you'd better
think of another way.
제가 할 수 있을 것 같습니다
I think I got it.
TV 광고죠
매우 겨냥된
TV commercial.
Highly targeted.
샌드파이퍼에선,
특정 시간에 기차가 운행됩니다
Let me tell you, at Sandpiper,
the trains run on time.
Mussolini가 자랑스러워하겠군요
Mussolini would be proud.
제가 방문했던 모든 사람들은,
다들 정확히 같은 일정을 진행합니다
Every one
I've visited so far,
아침 10시, 수중 에어로빅
same exact schedule.
10:00 a.m., water aerobics,
오후 2시, 라인 댄스
2:00 p.m., line dancing.
So on, and so forth.
그런 것들이요
그들은 항상 오후 3시부터 오후 4시까지
자유시간을 갖습니다
They always leave 3:00 p.m.
to 4:00 p.m. free.
왜냐구요?
때문이죠
Why? Murder, She Wrote.
It's been in syndication
since, like, the 1850s.
이건 마치 1850년대부터 독점적인 거에요
그리고 그 때가 되면,
And let me tell you,
when that thing comes on?
나방이 전기식 살충장치에 들어가듯
파란 머리칼을 그리는거죠
It draws the blue-hairs like
moths to a bug zapper.
오후 3시 14분,
제 1막의 절정 부분에서,
3:14 p.m., end of
the first act cliff-hanger.
첫 번째 광고가 나오죠, Davis & Main
First commercial up, Davis & Main.
Guaranteed eyeballs.
많은 사람들이 눈을 뜨고 볼 거에요
샌드파이퍼에선 그것 말고 할 게 없거든요
Lots of 'em.
There's nothing
Sandpiper can do about that.
우린 몇 년 전에 광고를 했었죠
We ran a commercial a few years
back, another class action case.
다른 집단 소송 건에 대해서요
우리에겐 새로운 일인 것 같네요
Kind of a new thing for us.
It's not exactly my go-to,
이건 확실히 내 일은 아닌 것 같네요
하지만 대충 말하자면,
저는 광고에 마음이 열려있습니다
but generally speaking,
I'm open to it.
다음 주에 얘기하도록 하죠
We will talk next week.
좋아요
조심히 가세요
Great! Safe travels.
당신 혹은 당신의 가족이
중피종이나 관련된 증상이라고
진단받았다면,
당신은 금전적 손해배상을
청구할 수 있습니다
중피종은 흔치 않은 폐 질환으로
Mesothelioma is
a rare lung disease
발암 물질로 잘 알려진 석면에
노출되는 것과 관련 있습니다
usually associated with
exposure to asbestos,
a known human carcinogen.
오랜 기간 석면 가루를 흡입하는 것은
Long-term inhalation
of asbestos fibers
악성 폐암, 중피종, 석면 침착증과 같이
can cause serious
or fatal illnesses
including malignant lung cancer,
mesothelioma and asbestosis.
심각하거나 치명적인 질병을 유발할 수 있습니다
그들이 저걸 제대로 하기 위해
정말 열심히 일했다는 걸 기억해주세요
I remember they worked real
hard to get that just right.
뭘 제대로 한다고?
To get what just right?
오, 저... 소용돌이요
Oh, the swirl.
그들은 흐릿하지만,
너무 과하게 흐릿하지 않은 걸 원했거든요
They wanted it kind of nebulous,
but not too nebulous.
그리고 속도의 문제도 있었구요
Then there was
the issue of the speed.
저것 때문에 정말
수많은 회의를 한 게 기억나네요
I remember there were a lot
of meetings about that.
왜 안 그랬겠어
I'll bet.
For your free consultation, call
Davis & Main at 505-242-7700.
Davis & Main에
505-242-7700으로 전화주세요
505-242-7700입니다
That's 505-242-7700.
Cliff가 이거에 승인했어?
Cliff signed off on this?
파트너들이 매우 좋아했어요
The partners were very happy.
어떻게 생각하시는데요?
What do you think?
내 생각엔...
I think...
Whatever happened
to showmanship?
쇼맨쉽은 어디로 간거야?
이거 봐봐
Yo. Check it out.
Ricola!
이봐!
Hey!
부모님이 투자해줄 정도로
프로처럼 연기해줄래?
Would you two ass-clowns
act like the professionals
your parents are
paying for you to become?
이거 엄청 비싼 걸거라고
This happens to
be very valuable.
정말요? 그게 뭔데요?
Yeah?
What is it?
이건, 어, Alpine 양치기 소년이야
This one is
the Alpine Shepherd Boy.
이건 그녀의 조카를 위한 거라고
It's for her nephew.
So, come on.
그러니까, 참여해
Join me. Production meeting.
Bring it in. All right.
제작 회의다, 일로 와
좋아요
이제, 봐봐, 팀워크는 멋진 결과를 만들거야
Now look, teamwork
makes the dream work.
우린 다같이 만들 수 있을거야
뭘 만드냐면...
Together, we can make something,
dare I say it, bravura.
내가 감히 말할 수 있을까?
바로 엄청난 작품을 말이지
And this is a golden opportunity,
especially for you guys,
그리고 이건 어마어마한 기회라고,
특히 너네들한테
'cause it's gonna play
all around the Southwest.
왜냐면 이건 남서부 전체에 방영될거거든
So, who knows what
it could lead to?
이게 뭘 가져다줄 지 누가 알겠어?
각각 100불이면 충분해요
Better lead
to 100 bucks each.
돈이랑 원수졌어?
What is it with you
and money?
VX2000을 사려고 저축 중이에요
Saving up for a VX2000.
Hey! Pop quiz. What do we three
have in common with the greats?
깜짝 퀴즈를 낼게
다음의 세 명이
공통으로 갖고 있는 게 뭘까?
Welles, Fellini, Bergman...
가장 중요한 공통점은?
Welles, Fellini, Bergman.
The biggies.
뭔데요?
What?
그들 셋 모두...
All three of them, to a man,
worked in the highly lucrative,
매우 수익성이 좋고
창조적으로 보람있는 광고계에서 일했지
creatively rewarding field,
of advertising.
그리고 오늘밤, 우린 그들과 함께한다
And tonight, we join them.
이건 자신감을 가질만한 일이야, 그치?
This is heady stuff, right?
좋아
그럼, 집중하라구
Okay. So, pay attention.
할머니로 시작할거고,
흔들 의자에 앉아있을거야
We open on granny,
and she is rocking.
그리고 앞으로 갔다 뒤로 갔다,
그냥 앞으로... 뒤로
So she's back and forth...
Just very back and forth.
그리고 나서, 매우 느리고 부드럽게,
And then, very slowly and
smoothly, the camera, uh...
카메라가, 어...
그녀를 향해 움직이지...
Moves towards...
Dolly?
- 이동식 촬영기요?
- 이동식 촬영기... 좋지
A dolly. Good, yeah.
여기서 이동식 촬영기 봤어?
You see a dolly here?
이동식 촬영기 안 가져왔어?
You guys
didn't bring a dolly?
네, 없어요
Nope. No dolly.
이동식 촬영기 가져오라고 안 했잖아요
You didn't ask for a dolly.
- 물어봤어야죠. 이동식 촬영기는 추가 장비라구요
- 맞아요
Gotta ask, dude.
Dolly's extra.
It's true.
좋아, 이동식 촬영기 없다
Okay. No dolly. Um.
음...
그럼 뭐 임기응변으로 해보지
We will improvise then.
날 봐
Stay with me.
그녀는 흔들고 있어
She's rocking,
she's shivering,
그녀는 몸이 떨리고 있어
그녀는 낡은 숄을 붙들고 있어
she's clutching at
a tattered shawl.
They turned the heat off on
her, these evil bastards.
사악한 악당들이 난방을 꺼버린거야
그녀는 춥고 배고프고, 그녀는 외로워
She's cold and hungry,
she's friendless.
이건 가슴이 찢어질 것 같은 얘기라고
This is
heart-rending stuff, man.
좋아, 이건 터무니없는 거짓말이고
이건 아름답게 흑백으로 찍을거야
Okay. It's a one-er. And it's
shot in glorious black and white.
할 수 있지?
We can do that, right?
네
Yeah.
그래서 그게 끝이에요?
So, that's it? Old lady in a chair?
That's your commercial?
늙은 여자가 의자에 앉아있는 거?
그게 당신의 광고에요?
누가 널 좋아하긴 하니?
Does anybody like you?
I'm ready for my close-up,
Mr. McGill!
촬영 준비 다 됐어요, McGill씨
It wasn't exactly set because
Perez wasn't back up in time.
Low ball. Strike one out right now.
Dale Carey at the plate.
Perez at first base.
3-2.
Bottom of the ninth inning.
And the pitch.
Perez is going...
And it's over left,
third baseman Nick Johnson.
Perez goes into third,
he slides, safe!
Perez gets all
the way around the bases.
Perez to third base.
Dale Carey still at first.
Looking to get to second. But he'll
stay at first. A great play.
좋은 하루 되세요
Morning.
무슨 일이니?
Hey, honey,
what's happening?
What's wrong?
뭐가 잘못됐어?
What happened?
무슨 일이야?
Where's Kaylee?
She's at school.
- Kaylee는?
- 학교에 있어요. 애는 괜찮아요
She's fine,
she doesn't know about it.
- 애는 이거에 대해 몰라요
- 괜찮니?
Are you all right?
Let me show you.
보여드릴게요
It's up,
it's up there.
저기에.. 저기 있어요
You see it?
It's right up there.
보이세요?
바로 저기 있어요
You see that?
You see the shape of it?
보여요?
저 모양이 보이세요?
보이는 거 맞죠?
You do see it, right?
I see it.
보인다
언제 총소리를 들었니?
What time did
you hear the shots?
2:13 this morning.
I looked at the clock.
새벽 2시 13분이요
시계를 봤어요
그 세 명이라구요
It was three of them,
It was exactly like last time.
지난 번이랑 정확히 똑같아요
And you didn't call
the police? Or did you?
경찰에 전화하지 않았겠지
혹시 했니?
No. I...
What's the point?
아뇨, 전...
무슨 의미세요?
Um...
어... 고정관념에서 벗어나보려 한다
I'm thinking
outside the box, but...
혹시 꿈을 꿨다거나 한 건 아니니?
Do you think maybe it's
possible that you dreamed it?
가끔 그런단다
It happens sometimes.
I didn't dream it, Mike, because I
didn't sleep a wink last night.
전 꿈 꾼 게 아니에요, Mike
왜냐면 저는 지난 밤에 잠깐도 자지 않았거든요
저건 총알이에요
That came from a bullet.
I mean,
it must have, it wasn't there
정말루요, 정말이라구요
before last night,
I promise you that.
지난 밤엔 저기 없었어요
And I,
I don't know what to...
정말 확신해요, 그리고 전 모르겠어요...
Okay.
알았다
- 알았어
- 세상에...
Jesus.
I mean, I was here.
I was here and you weren't.
제 말은, 전 여기 있었어요
전 여기 있었고, 당신은 없었어요
I believe you.
난 너를 믿는다
난 너를 믿어
All right.
알았다. 그거면 됐어
That's it. We're getting you
and Kaylee out of this house.
너랑 Kaylee랑 이 집을 떠나는거다
End of story.
그게 끝이야
너 이런 것들에 대해서 생각은 해봤어?
You ever wonder
about these things?
어떤 이런 거?
이거
뭐, 이건 대체 어떤 이야기가 있을까?
What things?
This. Like,
what's the story with these?
이 말을 처음 한 사람은 누구였을까
Who was it who first said, "Hey,
I know, a big bowl of balls!"
"공이 있는 큰 그릇이네요"
나도 몰라
그냥 집에 있었어
I don't know.
They came with the place.
말도 안돼
저것들은 이 세상에 있는 모든
브랜드 아파트에 있다니까
No shit.
They're in every corporate
apartment in the world.
성서같이 말야
They're like the
Gideon Bible.
이봐, 내 공그릇에 질투하지 말라고
Hey. Don't be jealous of my big
bowl of balls. It's unbecoming.
어울리지 않아
대체 왜 그들은 빈 꽃병을 갖고 있는거야?
Why do they all have
to have empty vases?
글쎄, 그게 법이야
Well, it's the law.
Plus, it's a metaphor.
게다가, 은유지
이건 말해야겠어
I gotta say, I will miss the
nail salon's vibrating chairs.
난 네일샵의 진동 의자가 그리울거야
음, 널 위해서라면,
이 곳에 있는 모든 의자를
진동으로 만들 수 있어
For you, I can make any chair
in this place vibrate.
준비됐어?
You ready for this?
오케이, 시작한다
Okay, here it goes.
너는 86살이고
You're 86 years old,
you're a resident
Colorado Springs에 있는
샌드스프링 거주자야
of Sandpiper,
Colorado Springs.
넌 이제 막 오후 간식 시간에
라임맛 젤리를 먹었어
You just finished your
afternoon snack, lime Jell-O.
라임, 알았어
너는 휴게실에 있고,
Lime. Got it.
You're in the day room, you're
watching your favorite TV program.
너는 너가 제일 좋아하는
TV 프로그램을 보고 있어
그게 뭐냐고?
And what's this? There's been
another murder in Cabot Cove?
Cabot Cove에 다른 살인 사건이 있었나요?
아닐거야
맞아
No!
Yes!
보안관은 손을 쓸 수가 없고,
그리고 한 번 더,
The sheriff is
in over his head.
And once again, Jessica Fletcher
has to put aside the novel
Jessica Fletcher가 쓰던 소설을 제쳐놓고
법의 집행을 돕게 되지
she's been writing,
and assist law enforcement.
그러던 중에!
Shocker! The killer
left behind a cryptogram.
살인자가 암호를 놔두고 갔어...
그리고~ 광고!
And commercial.
제 남편과 저는 수많은 세월동안
절약하고 저축하며 살았어요
My husband and I
scrimped and saved for so many years.
우린 목돈을 모으려고 최선을 다했죠
We did our best to
build a nest egg,
그리고 우린 저희 가족에게
짐이 되고 싶지 않았어요
so that we wouldn't be
a burden to our family.
Ronald가 세상을 떠난 후,
저는 요양원으로 들어갔답니다
After Ronald passed, I moved to
an assisted living facility.
좋은 곳이죠
그들은 그들이 모든 것을 돌봐준다고 했어요
A nice place.
They told me they'd take
care of everything. But...
그런데 어느 날, 그들이 말하길
제 모든 돈이 없어졌다고 하네요
Then one day, they said
all my money was gone.
어떻게 그럴 수가 있죠?
How could that be?
Where did it all go?
모두 어디로 간건가요?
- 저거 진짜 눈물 아니지, 그치?
- Visine이야
※ Visine: 안약 브랜드
That's not
a real tear is it?
It's Visine.
만약 당신이 샌드파이퍼 크로싱 시설이나
If you or a
loved one is a resident
of a Sandpiper
Crossing facility
다른 관련된 은퇴 시설의 거주자라면,
or other associated retirement
community, you may be eligible
당신은 보상을 받을 자격이 있습니다
to receive compensation.
For a free consultation,
무료 상담은
Davis & Main 법률 사무소로 전화주세요
505-242-7700
call the law offices of
Davis & Main at 505-242-7700.
505-242-7700입니다
That's 505-242-7700.
어때?
Well?
너가 만든거야?
You made that?
몇몇 영화과 학생들이랑?
With some film students?
내가 감독했어
I directed.
이건... 완전 전문가 수준인데
It looks professional.
그리고?
그리고 만약 내가 86살의
샌드파이퍼 거주자라면...
And?
And if I were an 86-year-old
Sandpiper resident,
전화 걸겠어
좋았어
I'd be dialing.
Yes! Up top.
하이파이브
그리고 이 모든 건 미국 변호사 협회의
And all made in accordance
with the rules and regulations
규칙과 규제를 준수하여 만들었어
of the American
Bar Association.
좋아
Good.
Davis & Main이 이걸 한다는 게 믿기지 않아
I can 't believe
Davis & Main went for it.
음...
나는 부서의 책임자잖아
Well, I'm in charge
of the department.
맞아, 그치만 Cliff Main이 이거에 괜찮다는 게
Yeah,
but still you know...
Cliff Main was fine with this.
그가 왜 그러지 않겠어?
Why wouldn't he be?
아냐, 이건... 이건 환상적이야
No, it's...
No, It's fantastic!
Let's celebrate. I'm getting more wine.
You want some?
축하하자
난 와인 좀 더 마실게
너도 좀 더 줄까?
당연하지
Absolutely.
Colorado에 있는 Colorado Springs요
Colorado Springs, Colorado.
네, 저는 11번 채널의 KKTV 번호를 알고 싶어요
Yeah, I'd like the number
for KKTV Channel 11.
Omar, FedEx 번호가 뭐지?
Omar!
What's the cut-off for FedEx?
택배 하나 보낼 게 있어, 빠르게
I need to get a package
out tout de suite.
Oh.
Uh, yes, can you connect me
to your ad sales department?
네, 광고 판매 부서로 연결해줄 수 있으신가요?
감사합니다
Thanks.
잇몸은 좋아보여요, 악화는 없네요
Gums look good.
No recession.
혀도 좋아보이구요
Tongue looks good, too.
귀도 깨끗해요
Eyes are clear.
이 조그만 숙녀분은 상태가 좋네요
This little
lady's in fine fettle.
당신이 원한다면 손톱을 깎아드릴 수 있어요
I could have one of the girls
trim her nails, if you like.
아뇨, 다음에요
No. Some other time.
무슨 일이 있나?
What do you got for me?
보디가드 일이요, 200 불
Bodyguard job. 200 bucks.
다른 건?
What else?
당신한텐, 제가 가진 것 중
그게 제일 잘 맞는 것 같네요
For you,
that's the best fit I've got.
I know a loan shark, always
needs enforcement and recovery.
제가 고리대금업자를 알아요
언제나 집행과 수금이 필요하죠
보수도 좋고, 안정적인 일이에요
Pays good
and it's steady work.
대부분은
Most of the time, we're
just talking intimidation.
그냥 말로만 협박할걸요
Strictly verbal.
"대부분은"이라
"Most of the time."
난 다리를 부러뜨리지 않아
I'm not breaking legs.
What else?
다른 건?
이봐요, 우리 이거에 대해 얘기했잖아요
Look, we discussed this.
You want next-level pay,
you gotta do next-level work.
당신은 좀 더 높은 보수를 원하고,
그럼 더 높은 일을 해야죠
저는 당신이 이런 일을 하는 걸 존중해요
I respect where you're
coming from on this thing,
I do.
But that's just how it goes.
정말로요
하지만 사는 게 다 그런거에요
알겠어요
All right.
She's gonna need a DHPP shot.
얘는 6개월 내에 DHPP 예방 접종을 해야 해요
In six months. We'll send
you a reminder card.
기억할 수 있게 카드를 드릴게요
그 때 까진
Until then.
보드가드 일을 주시오
Give me the bodyguard job.
200불 짜리요?
For 200?
시간과 장소를 전화로 알려드릴게요
I'll call you with
the where and the when.
그래서, 다들 아는거지...
So everybody knows to...
알아요
7700으로 시작하는 모든 회선은
They know.
Every line starting with 7700 has
been re-routed to the bullpen.
대기실로 안내돼요, 당신의 사무실까지도요
모두들 회선을 열린 상태로
둬야 한다는 걸 알고 있고요
Plus your office.
All the assistants
know to keep them open.
만약 너가 통화중일 때 다른 전화가 들어오면,
So if you're on a call
and another call comes in,
그 전화는 자동응답으로 넘어가지 않고, 맞지?
the call doesn't go to
an answering machine, right?
왜냐하면... 매우 중요하거든...
Because, very important, old people
don't like talking to robots.
나이 많은 사람들은
기계랑 대화하는 걸 싫어해
만약 제가 통화중일 때 다른 전화가 들어오면
If I'm on a call and
another call comes in,
Maida에게 넘어가요
they'll roll over to Maida.
그러고나면, Iris가 다음 것을 받고
After that, Iris will get the
next one, and then Julian,
다음은 Jilian, 그리고 Barbara
그리고 Yvonne, 쭉 따라 받을거에요
and then Barbara and Yvon.
Yeah.
Right on down the line.
좋아
그럼, 계획대로 해보자고
Good.
Let's make that the plan,
then.
Oh, so...
얼마나 남았지?
15분이네요
What time do you have?
Uh, quarter after. It should
be running now, right?
지금 재생되고 있을거에요, 그쵸?
다른 게... 더 있나요?
Is there anything else?
아냐. 고마워
No, thanks.
난 사무실에 있을게
It's...
I'll just be in my office.
제발
Come on.
제발, Colorado Springs, 제발
Come on, Colorado Springs...
Come on.
안녕하세요, Davis & Main, 법률 회사입니다
Good afternoon, Davis & Main.
Attorneys at law.
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
How may we help you?
Yes, ma'am. Yes,
ma'am, that is unfortunate.
네, 부인. 네, 그거 참 안타깝네요
당신의 사건을 맡을 변호사가 연락하기 위한
Now, to get your case started,
이름과 번호를 여쭤봐도 될까요?
may I ask for a name
and a number
안녕하세요, Davis & Main, 법률 회사입니다
for one of our
attorneys to reach you?
Good afternoon, Davis
& Main, attorneys at law.
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
How may we help you?
네, 맞습니다.
Good afternoon, Davis
& Main, attorneys at law.
안녕하세요, Davis & Main, 법률 회사입니다
Yes, sir. That is correct.
Good afternoon, Davis & Main.
One of our attorneys...
Good afternoon,
Davis & Main...
...one of our
attorneys get back to you.
안녕하세요, Davis & Main입니다
Give me one second,
샌드파이퍼 상담 전화입니다
- I'm just going to take down...
- Yes. That is correct...
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
And you're
currently a resident
at the Colorado
Springs facility?
Good afternoon,
Davis & Main...
네,부인
정보가 담긴 서류를 바로 보내드리겠습니다
Yes, ma'am.
We'll be happy to send an information
packet right out to you.
현재 샌드파이퍼 크로싱 시설의
May I ask,
are you currently a resident
거주자이신지 여쭤봐도 될까요?
of the Sandpiper
Crossing facility?
안녕하세요, Davis & Main입니다
안녕하세요, Davis & Main, 법률 회사입니다
빙고
그래서 현재 거주자이신지...
Bingo.
I'll just need
a name and a phone number.
그래
오늘 저녁에 일이 있어요
Yeah?
Something came in this evening
and it's definitely next level pay.
이건 확실히 더 높은 보수를 줄거에요
그래?
Yeah?
이건 아마 당신의 선택력에 따르면,
승산이 없을거에요
It's probably a long
shot given your selectivity.
What's the job?
일이 뭔가?
제가 물어봤지만 말해주지 않았어요
I asked,
the guy wouldn't tell me.
But whatever it is,
it's serious money.
하지만 그게 뭐든간에,
이거 대단한 돈이 될거에요
그리고 그 남자...
And the guy,
그 사람이 분명하게 당신을 원하더군요
he specifically asked for you.
그 사람이 누군데?
And who's the guy?
견딜 수 없습니다
I can't hold it, sir.
제어 불가능이에요, 선장님
No control on the planes, Captain.
We're going down and fast.
우린 빠르게 침몰하고 있어요
"우린 빠르게 침몰하고 있어요"
"We're going down and fast."
이거 봐봐
Check this out,
this is a good part.
이게 제일 좋은 장면이야
그래서, 다들 죽는거야? 거기까지만 말해봐
So do they all die?
Tell me that much.
Shh, shh, shh, shh!
쉬, 쉬, 쉬, 쉿!
Rock Hudson이 빙산으로 돌진하는거야?
Does Rock Hudson run
'em into an iceberg?
이거... 그가 했던 "McMillan& Wife"의 전이야 후야?
Is this before or after
he did McMillan & Wife?
Shut up. Watch the movie.
조용히 해. 영화나 봐
What is this weird
fascination you have
당신이 가진 이 이상한 취향은 뭐야?
with stories of men trapped
on the North Pole?
북극에 갇힌 남자의 이야기라니
는 북극이야
Ice Station Zebra
is on the North Pole.
The Thing takes
place on the South Pole.
은 남극에서 찍었고
They literally could not
be any more different.
그것들은 문자 그대로 차이가 없다고
우리 아빠가 이걸 좋아해
My Dad loves this one.
그래, 네 아빠랑 Howard Hughes가 그렇지
Yeah, him and Howard Hughes.
그러니까
I know, right?
그것보다 좋은 리뷰는 있을 수 없지
Can't get two finer
reviews than that.
산소 탱크에 얼마의 압력이 남았는가?
How much pressure
left in the air banks?
800 파운드 아래입니다, 선장님
Down to 800 pounds, sir.
Secure after group blow.
Mmm-mmm.
상사야
It's the boss.
이 시간에?
At this hour?
응
Yeah.
축하하기엔 늦은 시간이 아니지
Well, it's never too
late for congratulations.
Cliff, 세상에, 아직도 사무실에 있어요?
Cliff! Jesus,
you're still at the office?
당신이 광고를 보냈나요?
You ran a commercial?
Yeah. And, oh, my God, let me tell
you, the response has been...
네, 그리고 세상에나
말씀드리자면, 반응이 아주...
나한테 그걸 보여주지도 않고 광고를 보냈다고?
You ran a commercial without
ever showing it to me?
Without first consulting
me and my partners?
나랑 내 파트너들에게 보여주지도 않고?
당신 그게 실제로 방영될거라 생각했어요?!
Did you actually think
that was going to fly?
내일 아침에 말씀드리려 했어요
I was planning on
telling you in the morning.
방영되고난 다음날에?!
The day after it aired!
전 한 번 방영했을 뿐이에요,
그냥 하나의 작은 시장이라구요
I only ran it once.
Just in one small market.
실험적인거죠, 그쵸?
It was kind of an experiment,
all right
베타 테스트 같은 거라구요
kind of under the radar.
그리고 공정히 말하자면,
당신이 고객 응대는 제 할 일이라고 했어요
And in all fairness,
you did tell me client
outreach was my department.
의뭉스럽게 말하지 마요
Don't be disingenuous.
이 광고... 내 회사 이름이
나온 걸 받아들이라고?
This commercial, I take it
my firm's name is mentioned?
네, 그렇죠
Yes. Yeah.
세상에...
Jesus.
Howard가 당신이 조금 별나다곤 했지만
Howard said you were
a little eccentric.
당신이 빌어먹을 방화범인지는
말 안 했다고!
He didn't tell me you were
a goddamn arsonist!
Cliff, 공정하게 말하면,
제 생각에, 어...
Cliff, to be fair,
I don't think...
어...
Uh...
I apologize if there was any misreading
of the situation on my part.
제가 맡은 이 상황에
오해가 있었으면 사과해야겠네요
하지만 정말 좋은 소식이 있어요
But there's a very
positive headline here.
저흰 오늘 103 건의 전화를 받았어요
We got 103 phone calls today.
쥐꼬리만한 700불의 광고비를 제외하면요
Off a measly $700 ad buy!
이 정도의 투자 수익률은 얻을 수가...
Now, that kind of return on
investment, you can't...
내일 아침, 8시, 내 사무실에서,
파트너들이랑 봅시다
Tomorrow morning. 8:00.
My office, with the partners.
우린 이걸 봐야겠어요
And we want
to see this thing.
Cliff, 이걸 보게 되면, 당신은...
Cliff, when you see this,
I know you'll...
네, Cliff
Yeah, Cliff.
고마워요
Thank you. Yeah, you too.
네, 당신도요
네
다음에 봐요
Okay. See ya.
인기남 같으니
Golden Boy.
그게 나지
That's me.
그래서, 내가 뭘 놓쳤지?
So, what'd I miss?
Anything blow up yet?
아직 터진 건 없어?
조심하시지?
Feeling cautious?
우리가 여기서 뭘 하는 진
말해줘야 하지 않나?
You going to tell me
what we're doing here?
문제가 생겼다
I've got a problem.
- 좋아
- 이 문제는...
Okay.
This problem,
나 혼자 해결할 수가 없어
I can't solve it myself.
This problem,
is it a who or a what?
이 문제라... 사람 문제인가,
아니면 물건 문제인가?
사람이 하나 있어
There's a guy.
그를 없애고 싶어
I need him to go away.